As far as your new head coach, Jesse
Mentor.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, what was kind of for you the moment
in that process that you kind of
thought,
>> you know, he he he could be the the the
the next Ravens head coach?
>> I don't know if there was any one point
that it jumped out of me. It was just
kind of strong from the start and stayed
strong throughout. Uh, you know, our
first impression was fantastic. Those
guys had been here with Jess before, so
talked a little about them. uh got a
chance to you know do a little diligence
talking to Oz and some of the guys in
the building who have been with him but
then when I got a chance to meet him on
that first Zoom you know he's just very
impressive clear thinker
heard from a lot of people as I said at
the press conference around the league
unprompted like hey this is a real guy
that you guys ought to look at and and
Jess was impressive throughout the
process in terms of the way that he
approaches it alignment in terms of the
way we want to go about things
uh and the way we want to win and build
our organization and roster and team
play football. So, um just very
consistently positive throughout the
entire process.
>> How how important was that? You
mentioned the alignment. You know, you
move on from a long-term head coach, but
there's there's some thread there that
you know connected with the organization
before. It's not like you guys just rip
things up and move a different
direction. Yeah, we try to be incredibly
thoughtful first and respectful of John
and we challenged ourselves on that
decision as you know which was not an
easy decision as Steve shared.
I think when we sat and talked with
Jess, finding someone first of all
really going into the process, I think
understanding what we were looking for,
what we needed and why, pushing on that
quite a bit. We had a lot of good
discussion internally, Azie, Eric,
myself, Dick, Steve. So, when we we got
to the point where we're having
conversations with all candidates,
including Jesse, we had a really good
sense of what we were looking for. And
that alignment, I think, is really
important. So you can get into the
interview phase. Uh, and there's a ton
of just talented people out here that
are vying for these jobs, but it's
really important to know yourself and
what you think will be important for
your success long term. And Jess
represented embodied a lot of that.
>> Um, 101
minority matters just going through the
process yourself. Now, what do you think
we will do to move in the right
direction?
I think, you know, we're going to
consistently take a look at the process,
take a look at the pipeline, take a look
at ourselves, uh, in terms of where we
are. We had some incredible folks. I
mean, surprised, but we'll also say we
were really familiar with Jess, but also
surprised uh, that Vance didn't get a
look, and I think he will eventually.
He's going to have that defense running
again. Uh but you know ultimately we
need you know more talented folks in the
pipeline. We need to make sure the
pipeline's identifying those folks and
um that's going to be something that's
going to be a point of emphasis for the
league as we move forward. So you know
we want our fan bases, our front
offices, our coaching staffs to reflect
our locker rooms, our communities. Uh
and that's something that I said at my
first press conference. We're behind on
we need to get better at.
What were some of those non-negotiables
for the head coach? What were the head
coach must be?
>> Yeah, I think the first thing is always
start with character for us. You know,
we want someone who's got character as a
human being. Uh but also football
character, someone who's passionate
about the sport, uh has a lot of respect
for our community, is going to represent
us well throughout the state, Baltimore.
Uh and so that was really important to
us. That's really kind of the first
non-negotiable for us. We're going to
bring in someone who's going to be a
great teammate, great leader for
organization, Justin's going to be the
face of our franchise, we hope for a
very long time. Uh so beyond the talent,
which is also the other piece, you know,
someone who's really a teacher and a
great leader and an organizer of our
football program. Uh that's the other
piece, someone who's uh going to really
embody what we're we're looking for in
style of play, uh intensity,
the ability to, you know, be creative
and innovative as well. So we stay at
the forefront of uh concepts and tactics
and scheme uh but someone who's going to
be a great partner to Eric as well. You
know that partnership is incredibly
important. So
>> excuse me. I apologize. You guys have
taken a lot of hits in the court of
public opinion on the Max Crosby deal.
>> I have not noticed.
>> Are you concerned that that could impact
the organization's reputation? And I
don't believe we're going to talk to
Steve here. How frustrated is he that
the organization's sort of integrity is
getting challenged?
>> Yeah, I one I think it's a slow slow
news cycle. I don't want to at all
downplay the experience uh that uh that
Max had coming that we all had. The
Raiders, Ravens, Max, our locker room.
As Eric said, uh, we were incredibly
excited and just as equally, if not
more, disappointed that we weren't able
to pull off that transaction and bring
Max, uh, to Baltimore. Uh, I'm not going
to go too much deeper into that. To
answer your specific question, we've got
strong, long relationships across the
league. We have emphasized the
importance of doing things the right
way. We'll continue to do that. And we
understand that it is a
headline story because of its profile
and significance. Uh we believe, you
know, our relationships
to the extent that you need time to
repair them, people understand who we
are and what we're about. Our locker
room understands that as well. Uh but
when you have high-profile transactions
like this and opportunities like this,
it's unfortunate, but sometimes these
things do happen. No fault of Max's
certainly or ours or the Raiders. It's
just kind of where it played out.
because of how it played out. Are there
changes in the whole the trade process,
the new league gear process where you
can agree to trades and it can't be
announced that you like to see or is
that there's no you don't think there's
anything that this should spur?
>> I think this is how it should be
handled. I mean, I really do. Uh Jeff,
the the we're not aiming for that
result.
>> But when you have a high stakes
transaction like that, everybody needs
to have understand kind of what
conditions you're moving forward on. And
you know, I won't say much more than
that, but uh we understand we're
disappointed it didn't go through, but
we move on to the next to the next
opportunity. Do you feel like it was
even in that process where as you heard
you said about the criticism that you
feel has been maybe misconstrued or
mischaracterized?
>> Yeah, but we wouldn't get into that
publicly honestly. Um and um
we understand the need to report on, you
know, these these high-profile cases and
and certainly, but uh you know, as I
said, we're going to trust ourselves and
have a ton of respect for Max and treat
all this with the right privacy and
respect and dignity that it deserves.
to follow up on on Jeff's question. Have
there been any conversations,
you know, regard to whether you think
personally that that anything should
change about how that process works with
the two-day negotiating period and the
start of the league year. Do you think
the league is interested? Have they
spoken to you at all about it? You know,
just to see if they think anything
should change, other team, other clubs,
have other clubs, have you had any of
those kind of conversations just about
about the process, not
>> Yeah. You know, I listen, I think
there's steps that that teams take
consistently. I think we just saw
another team go through a very similar
circumstance. This is not the first time
it's going to happen. Uh it will not be
the last. Uh so, you know, I think
everybody wants to be prudent throughout
processes and uh it's unfortunate and
rare, especially in a high-profile case
like this. Um but that's why the
processes are in place.
any news about international games?
>> Not yet. Uh not yet. You know, we have
two opportunities. The Falcons who are
on our our list of scheduled opponents
and the Cowboys are the two
opportunities, but we have not been told
they have not selected other than I
think the Australia game. They have not
selected opponents.
>> I think I'm contractually obligated
every year to ask about uniform changes.
>> Oh,
>> the the the annual inquiry.
>> Yes. Uh we we as I've told you before,
we'll we'll always update you when the
time is right on the uniforms. So, and
and you guys know, we're going to be
last in line for the uh rivalry
uniforms, which I think have we would
start designing those in maybe a year.
So,
>> there was a tweet the other day that's
that spurred some speculation further on
on the uniforms.
>> Just one. There's always a tweet, you
know. It's always a tweet. Yeah. But the
the the core of like helmets and that
would not change as far as your
>> in the hypothetical situation.
>> You guys are good.
>> You guys are good, man. You guys are
good.
>> Way to bring it back around. That's
>> Yeah. You know, the process for
designing uniforms is a lengthy one. Um
so you you've got to go I think for
rivalry we'll start like a year and a
half in advance. Try to get through that
process. So, we'll let you guys know
when we're when when something's moving.
>> Sasha, you're moving into the third
phase of renovations or now. Um, but in
general, you guys are kind of at the
back end of when teams usually stay in
their stadium. Have you guys started
thinking about like longterm uh plans
for?
So, I think the renovations are a big
part of that.
Third phase, over $400 million invested,
significant of those dollars from from
us. Um, but thankful for the state.
We're really excited to bring the entire
project into fruition. Uh, starting this
summer and this last phase may be the
most significant and transformational
because the the plaza really stands up
and starts to take form. So, we are, as
you know, through Steve, just really
committed to learn from the lessons of
the past in Baltimore Memorial Stadium,
others to make sure we're delivering a
first class fan and game day experience
here in Baltimore. And Mnt Bank Stadium
has been at the forefront of game day
experiences and fan experiences as
ranked, you know, throughout its
history. This investment allows us, we
believe, to stay right at the front of
the pack despite the fact there have
been other new builds. Part of that is
because we have such an awesome fan base
in the flock. But the other piece of
that is because we put a lot of thought
into the experience that every fan is
going to have. So this plaza, the bump
out on the north plaza above in the
upper concourse, creation of new
bathrooms, you guys get that question
and comment a lot. I see them on on some
of your stories. Where are the
bathrooms? When are they coming? They're
coming. 33% increase in the bathrooms.
But the Northwest Plaza building will
bring live entertainment accessible to
every fan that comes in. Um, a ton of
technology that we're investing in on
the concourses, but also the plaza to
modernize the stadium. And the nice
thing, John, I think is that, you know,
we have a stadium that has the bones to
be able to continue invest
23 billion dollar tear down a new build.
Uh so we're blessed that way and we're
we're grateful for it. The complex is is
rolling. Excited to see the O's roll out
their first phase of renovations uh last
week at on opening day and so we're
really excited to deliver our stadium
renovations here uh this summer
completed.
>> Another uh hot topic in the league is
the 18 possibility of going to 18 games.
>> Where would the Ravens stance be for
that? I we'd leave that to the league
and I think the union to negotiate.
We're all watching it closely and you
know that's always going to have to be a
negotiation and compromise that works
for both sides. We have a ton of respect
for
where we think the players interests
are.
I think collectively both sides see an
opportunity, but we've got to work
through what that what that's going to
mean and how we make it work.
>> Another thing that could be changing the
league level is starting to see the talk
about renegotiating the TV deals that
could obviously change the economics of
the league and the game greatly. Are you
starting to sort of
>> put some variables into your future
planning in an organizational level or
is it too soon for this?
>> Too soon for this for us at an
organizational level. The league does a
great job of two things. One, keeping us
apprised of their plans and the work
that they're putting in on the media
side. Secondly, you know, I give a lot
of credit to Roger and his team, uh,
Hans, who's now running that group is to
stay on the front edge of,
you know, the innovations, the
technologies that need to happen. Our
fan base has remained very strong. where
they find the games or where we find
them to deliver games to them has been
disrupted quite a bit. And I think when
I first got here, you all were asking me
questions about the Thursday night
package on Prime and you know, some of
those things have become normalized now.
But the league has done a nice job of
monitoring and structuring our media
contracts and are finding new partners
and technology streamers uh to deliver
our game to where our fans are. um
particularly I think important for us as
we try to find younger fans um and how
they consume our our content in in our
live games.
>> Speaking of the the league, I think it
was a couple years ago that you guys
your pat so to speak for the draft in
Baltimore and where is that process at
with you guys?
>> Yeah, we're still in communications,
active communication with the league.
These are rolling processes where the
league gets a chance to know the local
market. Uh we're very much uh working
with our public civic partners, Visit
Baltimore, the city of Baltimore, the
state, but also um in communication with
the league. And I think we're going to
have we already have and I think we're
going to continue to have really strong
prospects bringing the draft, but until
that happens, um you know, we'll be
working at it very hard.
>> And the idea would be to utilize the
stadium or some portion of it.
That's TBD. But another good good shot
at trying to get me to roll out our
plans before we get a get a chance to
really really finalize. We know. But in
all seriousness, I think um there's a
lot of assets in and around Baltimore
that make it tremendously unique. The
harbor, the development around we have
one of the most unique sports complex
with a baseball stadium and uh a
football stadium that that you can see
each other, you know, from from our
parking lots and from our upper decks uh
concourses. So there's a lot of
opportunity for us to do some really
creative things and of course the city
has two beautiful massive parks. You've
seen those utilized different places. Uh
so there's a lot of opportunity and we
are exploring all of those uh potential
sites.
>> Continuing the draft conversation. Um
how much do you guys hope the roughly
match that you are will help you guys?
I think it's a great opportunity for us
to showcase as was the Messi game,
right? That the Mid-Atlantic, Baltimore
in particular, Maryland has a very, very
strong appetite for all kinds of sport.
Uh, our team enjoys tremendous support
from our fan base. They are also hungry
for
European football, soccer, global
football, um, rugby and and other
sports. We've I think we've talked about
why are the stadium renovations
important? There's a lot of reasons
they're important. One of the reasons is
we want the stadium Steve's commitment
to being downtown Baltimore to drive
more people, fan activity downtown
Baltimore. And you all know we have six
nights of events uh that are coming to
Mnt Bank outside of Ravens games this
year. So that's incredibly important for
us to deliver on that objective that we
set with the state when we renovated.
And I think the international match puts
us on a global scale a little bit like
the AFC Championship did where you know
just there's so many people around the
world and around the country watching
South Africa, New Zealand, you can't
find a more significant kind of
international iconic matchup. Uh so
credit to our teams Brad Down who went
out and hunted that opportunity and
brought it back to our stadium. Rich
Tomio who's here uh as well has done a
tremendous job at attracting global
international events. Mnt Bank Stadium
in Baltimore.
>> Have you guys decided on ticket prices?
Is there going to be an increase this
year?
>> We have uh not decided on that yet. Um,
so we will announce that at the right
time. Um, Jeff, so sorry about that. But
yeah,
>> Sasha, this off season has done a lot
for the organization overall.
>> Yeah, lot of change
>> professionally and personally. What have
you kind of learned about yourself
dealing with the the different change?
Yeah, it's been the first time we've had
really significant change in almost two
decades, right? And Steve talked about
this. We
committed to avoid being an organization
that relies on change to get where we
think there's a lot of value to making
finding good people, committing to them,
pushing through adversity.
And so I think this is the first
opportunity for Eric at the helm, myself
to go through a coaching search and work
together with Steve, with Azie, with
with Dick at points as well through that
process. I think we worked well
together. Um, and there were others
involved certainly, but I think it was
an important opportunity for us to bring
all of our unique experiences
and and expertise to a coaching search.
But there was more than that. You know,
with every coaching search, a lot comes.
You guys seen we've hired some new
people, structured things a little bit
differently. So, it's a great
opportunity for us to step back, look at
the way we've done things for the better
part of the last two decades, uh, and
make some changes, move forward that we
think are going to position us as well
as possible. Most importantly, I think
we worked really well together through
change, adversity, uh, and opportunity.
>> Sasha, young, not to ask you a question
that I know you're probably not going to
answer, but uh, Lamar, not so much on
the contract negotiation stuff.
Eric's talked about that, but what have
you, I guess, seen um in this process?
You know, they Eric's talked about a
little bit, Jesse, as well in terms of
Lamar's involvement in the process when
you guys were hiring uh the coach
and what have you seen, I guess, from
the engagement standpoint and and what
level of confidence do you guys have
that will have an extension? Yeah,
Lamar's,
you know, at a point in his career where
he's seen so much. So, we value his
opinion tremendously. He knows and has
shaped and led our organization.
And so, it was great to have his
involvement. You guys talked to Jess
about his interaction with him through
his his process.
Same with Eric. uh he and Lamar have
been in contact and so you know it's
nice to have that engagement
and I think there's just a tremendous
amount of respect for what he brings to
the table and what we're going to be
able to do together. I'll defer all the
as you guys know uh no different than
when Dick was here. I'll defer all the
contract discussions out of respect for
Lamar but also the organization to Eric
and he'll be able to answer those.
your team being recognized by their
peers across the league. Um I'm curious
what does that mean to you and how do
they help you at all?
>> Yeah, so Eric Oz the organization have
done a great job at positioning us to
try to find competitive advantage. One
area that I think that's been um we
don't publicize much uh but is in the
area of just kind of football operation
intelligence. We also have stood up a
group on the business side for business
intelligence that works separately from
that. Uh so we're grateful to have in
this era of just the the dynamic power
value of having innovation, technology,
data available to help us make great
decisions. Uh and to have I think
leadership on both sides of organization
that really invests and believes in
process and information so that we can
make the best possible decisions. The
big decisions we're making, we needed to
get them right. And uh I think our our
team top to bottom is really strong on
both sides of the organization.
>> Is that it?
>> One more on
>> Yeah.
>> Obviously with respect to to privacy in
NAB and Eric has talked about that and
sort of leaving it up to him to address
that. Is there um I guess where would
you gauge the organization's
um optimism sense of where things are at
timeline of how you know things will
develop as we get toward the offseason
program here couple weeks at
>> TBD be too early to to appine or express
any optimism or pessimism? Don't read
into it one way or the other. uh you
know he's going to have to get himself
to a point uh you know here where you
know he and Eric are I'm sure going to
have plenty of conversation until that
time and and even when that time comes
I'll let Eric comment but um I don't
take it as pessimism or optimism it's
just got to go through the process